Mouse

General Buttons

LButton The left mouse button when used with Send, but the primary mouse button when used with hotkeys. In other words, if the user has swapped the buttons via system settings, LButton:: is physically activated by clicking the right mouse button, but Send {LButton} performs the same as physically clicking the left button. To always perform a logical left click, use Click Left or Send {Click Left}. 
RButton The right mouse button when used with Send, but the secondary mouse button when used with hotkeys. In other words, if the user has swapped the buttons via system settings, RButton:: is physically activated by clicking the left mouse button, but Send {RButton} performs the same as physically clicking the right button. To always perform a logical right click, use Click Right or Send {Click Right}. 
MButton Middle or wheel mouse button 

Advanced Buttons

XButton1 4th mouse button. Typically performs the same function as Browser_Back. 
XButton2 5th mouse button. Typically performs the same function as Browser_Forward. 

Wheel

WheelDown Turn the wheel downward (toward you). 
WheelUp Turn the wheel upward (away from you). 
WheelLeft
WheelRight 
[v1.0.48+]: Scroll to the left or right.

Requires Windows Vista or later. These can be used as hotkeys with some (but not all) mice which have a second wheel or support tilting the wheel to either side. In some cases, software bundled with the mouse must instead be used to control this feature. Regardless of the particular mouse, Send and Click can be used to scroll horizontally in programs which support it.
 

Keyboard

Note: The names of the letter and number keys are the same as that single letter or digit. For example: b is the B key and 5 is the 5 key.

Although any single character can be used as a key name, its meaning (scan code or virtual keycode) depends on the current keyboard layout. Additionally, some special characters may need to be escaped or enclosed in braces, depending on the context. [v1.1.27+]: The letters a-z or A-Z can be used to refer to the corresponding virtual keycodes (usually vk41-vk5A) even if they are not included in the current keyboard layout.

General Keys

CapsLock CapsLock (caps lock key) 
Note: Windows IME may interfere with the detection and functionality of CapsLock; see CapsLock and IME for details.
 
Space Space (space bar) 
Tab Tab (tabulator key) 
Enter Enter 
Return Deprecated: Use the synonym Enter instead to reduce ambiguity. 
Escape (or Esc) Esc 
Backspace (or BS) Backspace 

Cursor Control Keys

ScrollLock ScrollLock (scroll lock key). While the Ctrl key is held down, the ScrollLock key produces the key code of CtrlBreak, but can be differentiated from Pause by scan code. 
Delete (or Del) Delete 
Insert (or Ins) Insert 
Home Home 
End End 
PgUp PageUp (page up key) 
PgDn PageDown (page down key) 
Up ↑ (up arrow key) 
Down ↓ (down arrow key) 
Left ← (left arrow key) 
Right → (right arrow key) 

Numpad Keys

Due to system behavior, the following keys seperated by a slash are identified differently depending on whether NumLock is ON or OFF. If NumLock is OFF but Shift is pressed, the system temporarily releases Shift and acts as though NumLock is ON.

Numpad0 / NumpadIns 0 / Insert 
Numpad1 / NumpadEnd 1 / End 
Numpad2 / NumpadDown 2 / ↓ 
Numpad3 / NumpadPgDn 3 / PageDown 
Numpad4 / NumpadLeft 4 / ← 
Numpad5 / NumpadClear 5 / typically does nothing 
Numpad6 / NumpadRight 6 / → 
Numpad7 / NumpadHome 7 / Home 
Numpad8 / NumpadUp 8 / ↑ 
Numpad9 / NumpadPgUp 9 / PageUp 
NumpadDot / NumpadDel . / Delete 
NumLock NumLock (number lock key). While the Ctrl key is held down, the NumLock key produces the key code of Pause, so use ^Pause in hotkeys instead of ^NumLock. 
NumpadDiv / (division) 
NumpadMult * (multiplication) 
NumpadAdd + (addition) 
NumpadSub - (subtraction) 
NumpadEnter Enter 

Function Keys

F1 - F24 The 12 or more function keys at the top of most keyboards. 

Modifier Keys

LWin Left Win. Corresponds to the <# hotkey prefix. 
RWin 
Right Win. Corresponds to the ># hotkey prefix.

Note: Unlike Control/Alt/Shift, there is no generic/neutral "Win" key because the OS does not support it. However, hotkeys with the # modifier can be triggered by either Win key.
 
Control (or Ctrl) Control. As a hotkey (Control::) it fires upon release unless it has the tilde prefix. Corresponds to the ^ hotkey prefix. 
Alt Alt. As a hotkey (Alt::) it fires upon release unless it has the tilde prefix. Corresponds to the ! hotkey prefix. 
Shift Shift. As a hotkey (Shift::) it fires upon release unless it has the tilde prefix. Corresponds to the + hotkey prefix. 
LControl (or LCtrl) Left Control. Corresponds to the <^ hotkey prefix. 
RControl (or RCtrl) Right Control. Corresponds to the >^ hotkey prefix. 
LShift Left Shift. Corresponds to the <+ hotkey prefix. 
RShift Right Shift. Corresponds to the >+ hotkey prefix. 
LAlt Left Alt. Corresponds to the <! hotkey prefix. 
RAlt 
Right Alt. Corresponds to the >! hotkey prefix.

Note: If your keyboard layout has AltGr instead of RAlt, you can probably use it as a hotkey prefix via <^>! as described here. In addition, LControl & RAlt:: would make AltGr itself into a hotkey.
 
